Guide to the Thaddeus Sheldon Papers on Harmonia, 1853-1868 DAR.1960.01
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Harmonia documents, I.
  - "Seven Reasons for Obtainment of Legal Divorce," by J. M. Spear [written on the back of an application to join the Order], June 5, 1863 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - "Twelve Reasons for Open and Public Marriage," by J. M. Spear, June 7, 1863 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - "To the President," by J. M. Spear, June 10, 1863 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - "Of the White Robes," "Of the Whore," "Of Covenants Written, or Other Obligations," by J. M. Spear, June 11-17, 1863 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - "Of Agreements and Disagreements," J. M. Spear, June 18, 1863 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - "A General Epistle to the More Immediate Friends of the New Social Scheme," J. M. Spear, June 25, 1863 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - "The Future of America," by J. M. Spear, June 27, 1863 (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - "Arrival in the Old World," J. M. Spear, June 30, 1863 (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Schedule of papers to be transmitted [J. M. Spear], July 1-2, 1863 (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - "Statement of the Case," J. M. Spear, July 13, 1863 (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - "Premonitions," J. M. Spear, July 15, 1863 (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - "Premonitions II and III," J. M. Spear, July 16, 1863 (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - "To the President," J. M. Spear, July 21, 1863 (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - "Of Business Action," by J. M. Spear, July 26, 1863 (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - "Of the Economics," by J. M. Spear, July 31, 1863 (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - "New England Business Action," J. M. Spear, August 3, 1863 (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - "Propositions,"J. M. Spear, August 11, 1863 (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - "Power of Attorney," signed Benjamin Franklin [J. M. Spear], August 12, 1863 (Box 3, Folder 56)
  - "Business Details," by J. M. Spear, August 14, 1863 (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - "Thoughts for the Specificatoress and others," by J. M. Spear, August 17, 1863 (Box 3, Folder 58)
  - John Orvis to T. S. Sheldon, August 17, 1863 (Box 3, Folder 59)
  - "Of Compensation," by J. M. Spear, August 19, 1863 (Box 3, Folder 60)
  - "Of Gold, Silver and the Other Precious Metals," by J. M. Spear, August 20, 1863 (Box 3, Folder 61)
  - "Of the Employment of Negroes, Mulattoes, etc.," by J. M. Spear, September 3, 1863 (Box 3, Folder 62)
  - "Of the Action of the Superior upon the Inferior," by J. M. Spear, September 4, 1863 (Box 3, Folder 63)
  - "Of Attraction, Restraint and Compulsion," by J. M. Spear, September 5, 1863 (Box 3, Folder 64)
  - "Of the Communicative Branch of the Social Scheme," signed Benjamin Franklin [J. M. Spear], September 24, 1863 (Box 3, Folder 65)
  - "Last Words," [J. M. Spear], September 29, 1863 (Box 3, Folder 66)
  - "Plan of Action to the Leading Mind of the General Assembly," J. M. Spear, October 12, 1863 (Box 3, Folder 67)
  - "To the Apostle of Harmony," signed Benjamin Franklin [J. M. Spear], December 29, 1863 (Box 3, Folder 68)
  - Isabelle Priget to Mr. Pearce, January 1864 (Box 3, Folder 69)
  - John B. Conklin to Samuel Cuppy, January 12, 1864 (Box 3, Folder 70)
  - Broadside for the Spirit-Power Institute [with handwritten note from Spear to Sheldon at bottom], February 25, 1864 (Box 3, Folder 71)
  - J. G. Davey to J. M. Spear, March 15, 1864 (Box 3, Folder 72)
  - Schedule of things to be done while at Paris by J. M. Spear, March 15, 1864 (Box 3, Folder 73)
  - J. W. Cunningham to J. M. Spear, March 18, 1864 (Box 3, Folder 74)
  - F. Cantagrel to Monsieur Laverdant [in French], April 1, 1864 (Box 3, Folder 75)
  - "Of the Philosophy of Struggle," with a letter by Spear to Sheldon, April 12, 1864 (Box 3, Folder 76)
  - John Sterling to Brother Sheldon, September 5, 1864 (Box 3, Folder 77)
  - Henry S. Fitch to Dear Sheldon, October 6, 1864 (Box 3, Folder 78)
  - "The Opening of the Book of Life," initialed A. S. W. and B. F. [J. M. Spear], October 24, 1864 (Box 3, Folder 79)
  - "Methods of Action," initialed A.S.W. and B. F. [J. M. Spear], October 25, 1864 (Box 3, Folder 80)
  - Thomas and Anne Etchells to Mr. and Mrs. John Murray Spear, November 5, 1864 (Box 3, Folder 81)
  - J. Murray Spear to My Dear Brother, November 22, 1864 (Box 3, Folder 82)
  - J. Murray Spear to My Dear Friend Sheldon, November 22, 1864 (Box 3, Folder 83)
  - J. Buffum to Friend Thaddeus, December 13, 1864 (Box 3, Folder 84)
  - J. Buffum to T. S. Sheldon, December 15, 1864 (Box 3, Folder 85)
  - F. B. Guthrie to William Howland, December 17, 1864 (Box 3, Folder 86)
  - John Sterling to Brother Sheldon, December 25, 1864 (Box 3, Folder 87)
  - J. Buffum to Thaddeus Sheldon, January 3, 1865 (Box 3, Folder 88)
  - G. B. Ferguson to Mr. and Mrs. Spear, January 19, 1865 (Box 3, Folder 89)
  - Financial account [by Mrs. Spear], January 25, 1865 (Box 3, Folder 90)
  - J. M. S. to Carrie [Lewis], January 31, 1865 (Box 3, Folder 91)
  - Specificatoress [Mrs. Spear] to Dearest Harmonizer, January 31, 1865 (Box 3, Folder 92)
  - A.S.W. [Associated Spirit World] to the American Agent, February 1, 1865 (Box 3, Folder 93)
  - J. Murray Spear to My dear Brother, February 2, 1865 (Box 3, Folder 94)
  - O. G. Chase to Brother Sheldon, February 13, 1865 (Box 3, Folder 95)
  - Jonathon Buffum to Friend Thaddeus, February 20, 1865 (Box 3, Folder 96)
  - John Sterling to Brother Sheldon, March 3, 1865 (Box 3, Folder 97)
  - Jonathan Buffum to my dear Friend, March 15, 1865 (Box 3, Folder 98)
  - Specss. [Mrs. Spear] to my dear brother, March 17, 1865 (Box 3, Folder 99)
  - John Sterling to Brother Sheldon, March 26, 1865 (Box 3, Folder 100)
  - John Sterling to Brother Sheldon, March 31, 1865 (Box 3, Folder 101)
  - John Sterling to Brother Sheldon, May 6 and 14, 1865 (Box 3, Folder 102)
  - John Orvis to My dear Brother, May 7, 1865 (Box 3, Folder 103)
  - A.S.W. [J. M. Spear] to the American Agent, May 14, 1865 (Box 3, Folder 104)
  - [The Spears] to Dear Brother [Sheldon], May 15, 1865 (Box 3, Folder 105)
  - Caroline Spear to My dear brother [Sheldon], May 29, 1865 (Box 3, Folder 106)
  - John Orvis to Brother Sheldon, June 15, 1865 (Box 3, Folder 107)
  - J. Murray Spear to my dear brother, June 15, 1865 (Box 3, Folder 108)
  - John Orvis to Brother Sheldon, June 20, 1865 (Box 3, Folder 109)
  - "Address to the People of America," by J. M. Spear, March 9, 1866 (Box 3, Folder 110)
  - "To the President," signed Benjamin Franklin [J. M. Spear], June 4, 1868 (Box 3, Folder 111)
  - Untitled, [T. S. Sheldon],ca. 1854 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Untitled, [T. S. Sheldon], ca. 1854-1856 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - "Faith in Principles," [T. S. Sheldon] (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - "Of Heroism," [T. S. Sheldon], ca. 1854-1856 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Untitled, [T. S. Sheldon], ca. 1854-1856 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Untitled, [T. S. Sheldon], ca. 1854-1856 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - "Of Events," [T. S. Sheldon], ca. 1854-1856 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Untitled, [T. S. Sheldon], ca. 1854-1856 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - "Of Fidelity to Principles," [T. S. Sheldon], ca. 1854-1856 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - "Of Agriculture," [T. S. Sheldon], ca. 1854-1856 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - "When is God-Who is God-What is God," [T. S. Sheldon], ca. 1854-1856 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - "Of Health," [T. S. Sheldon], ca. 1854-1856 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Untitled, [T. S. Sheldon], ca. 1854-1856 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - "Of Association," [T. S. Sheldon], ca. 1854-1856 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Untitled, [T. S. Sheldon], ca. 1854-1856 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Untitled, [T. S. Sheldon], ca. 1854-1856 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - "Of Government," [T. S. Sheldon], ca. 1854-1856 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - "Of Onanism," [T. S. Sheldon], ca. 1854-1856 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Broadside for The Educator, 1857 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - "Of Education," [T. S. Sheldon], ca. 1857 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Moral Police Fraternity Constitution and Letter of Instruction, ca. 1858 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Untitled [T. S. Sheldon], ca. 1858 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - "Birthology," [T. S. Sheldon], ca. March 30, 1858 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Untitled, [T. S. Sheldon], ca. 1859 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - "Mission of the Apostle of Harmony," signed Esther from Queen [T. S. Sheldon], ca. 1859 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - "Basis of a Bread Association," by J. M. Spear, ca. 1859 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - "Announcement of the Organization of the Sacred Order," [J. M. Spear], ca. December 1859 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - List of rules to be observed while on the river expedition, written by J. M. Spear, ca. December 1859 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - "The Merchant," [T. S. Sheldon], ca. 1860 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - "Address to the American People, Number Two," signed S. M. J., ca. 1860 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Hewitt to dear Sterling, ca. 1860 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Broadside for The Unionists, ca. 1860 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Prospectus for the Pilot Knob Iron Company, ca. 1861 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - "What A Merchant Should Be!" [T. S. Sheldon], ca. 1861 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - "Invocation,"by J. M. Spear, ca. 1862 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Untitled, by J. M. Spear, ca. 1862 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - "Of Industrial Organizations," by J. M. Spear, ca. 1862 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - "Of Methods of Action," by J. M. Spear, June 5, 1863 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - "Of Incentives,"by J. M. Spear, ca. 1863 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Address to the Direct Owners and Managers of the Machine, [T. S. Sheldon], ca. 1863 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - "A Business Statement," by J. M. Spear, ca. 1863 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Untitled, [J. M. Spear], ca. 1863 (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - "My Scheme of Management," by J. M. Spear, March 1863 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Untitled, [J. M. Spear], ca. 1864 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - J. M. Spear business card, ca. 1864 (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - J. Chapman poem "To A Skylark," [with note by Spear on back], ca. 1864 (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - "Business Agreement," by J. M. Spear, ca. 1864 (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - "Propositions," by T. S. Sheldon, ca. 1864 (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - "To the Apostle of Harmony," signed Benjamin Franklin [J. M. Spear], ca. 1864 (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - List of Papers Given in Paris from April 7-May 15, ca. 1864 (Box 4, Folder 50)
  - John Sterling to T. S. Sheldon, ca. 1865 (Box 4, Folder 51)
  - Invocation, ca. April 2, 1865 (Box 4, Folder 52)
  - Envelope Addressed to T. S. Sheldon, ca. October 25, 1865 (Box 4, Folder 53)
- Ernest C. Miller Correspondence and Research, II.
  This series contains correspondence, handwritten transcripts, Photostats, and items relating to research of Harmonia, much of which are typewritten copies, particularly the excerpts from books and articles.
  - Typewritten notes and a Photostat of a newspaper clipping about Kiantone, undated (Box 4, Folder 54)
  - Resume of writings of John Murray Spear, leader of Harmonia, undated (Box 4, Folder 55)
  - Typewritten copy of "The Kiantone Movement," by Oliver F. Chase (Box 4, Folder 56)
  - Clipping of article by Ray Finch titled "Fabled Harmonia Lingers in Spirit", September 1, 1949 (Box 4, Folder 57)
  - Article from Time about the North American Phalanx, May 16, 1949 (Box 4, Folder 58)
  - The Kiantone Valley and the Association of Beneficents, unpublished speech by William S. Bailey, June 27, 1924 (Box 4, Folder 59)
  - Hand-drawn map of Kiantone Harmonia, undated (Box 4, Folder 60)
  - Correspondence between Ernest C. Miller and T. D. Seymour Bassett, December 10, 16, and 19, 1947 (Box 4, Folder 61)
  - Handwritten notes about Harmonia, undated (Box 4, Folder 62)
  - Handwritten copy of Thaddeus S. Sheldon's diary entries from May 17, 1849 to February 24, 1866, undated (Box 4, Folder 63)
  - Correspondence between Ernest C. Miller and Josephine G. Myers, July 1947-February 1949 (Box 4, Folder 64)
  - Photostat of September 26, 1933 report of water analysis of Spiritual Springs water (Box 4, Folder 65)
  - Ernest C. Miller correspondence, February 1947-June 1948 (Box 4, Folder 66)
  - Library references and correspondence, August 1946-March 1950 (Box 4, Folder 67)
  - Correspondence between Ernest C. Miller and Arthur E. Bestor, Jr., May 1948-March 1950 (Box 4, Folder 68)
  - Typewritten excerpts from Interior Causes of the War: The Nation Demonized, and Its President a Spirit-Rapper, by David Quinn, undated (Box 4, Folder 69)
  - Typewritten information about Dr. O. W. Wellington, undated (Box 4, Folder 70)
  - Notes compiled by Ernest C. Miller about the history of the Kiantone Valley Spiritualist Community, November 1941 (Box 4, Folder 71)
  - Clipping from Life about octagonal houses (Box 4, Folder 72)
  - Typewritten transcript of an interview with John M. Cushman, January 21, 1949 (Box 4, Folder 73)
  - Photostat of article from Cleveland newspaper titled "Utopia-The Lost Dream City (The City of Spiritual Springs),"by E. George Lindstrom, April 17, 1938 (Box 4, Folder 74)
  - Correspondence between Ernest C. Miller and Margaret M. Fish (Thaddeus Sheldon's granddaughter), April 1951 and April-May 1957 (Box 4, Folder 75)
  - Broadside for The Educator, 1857 (Box 4, Folder 76)
  - Photostat of The New Era: Or Heaven Opened to Man, June 28, 1854 (Box 4, Folder 77)
  - Typewritten transcript of an January 13, 1949 interview with Gerald G. Staples and correspondence, May 1948-June 1949 (Box 4, Folder 78)
  - Ernest C. Miller correspondence with the New York Public Library, February 1949 (Box 4, Folder 79)